<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[La Musica de Latinoamerica]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[La Musica de Latinoamerica]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/chuyak/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 21:54:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/chuyak/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Inkas]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Los Inkas</h1><p>Spanish conquest introduced several major changes to the Andean musical world. First, the introduction of string instruments and, second, the western musical scales: Major and minor keys, sharps and flats. The standard key for most Andean flutes is G major. Nevertheless, the combination of Andean woodwinds and Spanish strings is a fairly recent development. Typically, most people are exposed to the classic Andean sounds of the kena and siku, accompanied by guitar, charango and the bombo. This is emblematic of what musicologists refer to as the “Pan-Andean” movement. Traced back to the late nineteen fifties and nineteen sixties, this followed the migration of rural indigenous people to the large urban centers in search of work, with the introduction of Andean pipes into the urban setting and the inevitable mixture with “criollo” culture. The “criollo” culture refers to the mestizo, or mixed race culture, that is the product of European and indigenous ethnicities. Musically speaking, no instrument better exemplifies this than the charango. The charango is a string instrument that embodies the combination of these two cultures. It is descended from the vihuela de mano (hand-lute), brought by Spaniards from the Mediterranean. The instrument was copied by the indigenous population, and the end result was a new and unique addition to Andean folk music. Many people credit the town of Potosí, Bolivia, as the birth place of the charango. Peruvians, on the other hand, tend to disagree, arguing that the charango comes from Ayacucho, Peru.</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/9b65e60d-d6b2-4047-978f-f4977c98c8f2.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chuyak/75507de8-041a-4af6-bc3d-d21d94c8bc80/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">75507de8-041a-4af6-bc3d-d21d94c8bc80</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 21:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Andes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Los Andes</h1><p>The haunting sounds of bamboo pipes have formed a part of the Andean landscape for over two millennia. The Andean melodies most people are exposed to today, however, are a result of centuries of colonialism and the migrations of peoples from different regions and continents. Let’s take a look at how all this happened.</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/1f53d675-c2b5-4060-9446-8a9b623bee8b.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.theverge.com/2015/11/5/9671564/lytro-immerge-light-field-vr-video-camera</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">31a786f8-4110-4600-b379-30ae3f504894</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 21:42:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>